Taft, Philip Papers 5541
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series II. Research/Subject Files
  - Steel - United Steelworkers, 1942-1947 (Box 10, Folder 38)
    Two unsigned typescripts: ("The United Steelworkers of America," n.d., 2 pages; "The United States Steel Corporation," c. 1961, 4 pages; memorandum from [CIO] General Counsel Lee Pressman to staff re "Securing Data Relevant to Discharges for Union Activities," n.d.; "Brief Report of the Progress of the United Steelworkers of America, District #36, since Jun3 1942," n.d.; minutes of AFL Executive Council, February 4, 1945, 4 pages; "International Officers and District Directors of the United Steelworkers of America," June 1, 1947, 3 pages
  - Steel - United Steelworkers - Elections, 1965-1967 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    "The Steelworkers Election," unattributed 78 page manuscript, August 1965; numerous commission reports and election appeal briefs, 1967
  - Steel - Notes, 1901-1942 (Box 10, Folder 40)
    Very numerous notes
  - Steel - Photocopies of Clippings, 1903-1947 (Box 10, Folder 41)
    Numerous (apparently incomplete) photocopies of articles from the AAISTW Amalgamated Journal and other journals, including the Jones and Laughlin decision
  - Stove Molders, 1887 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Street Railway Employees of America, 1892-1937 (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Strikes - (1) Taft Manuscripts, 1950-1960 (Box 10, Folder 44)
    Several typed manuscripts by Philip Taft, some unsigned, some fragmented, mostly re strikes in general, some re arbitration
  - Strikes - (2) "Important Material, 1875-1967 (Box 10, Folder 45)
    Mostly typed notes from various sources
  - Strikes - (3) Miscellaneous Material, 1912-1968 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    "Comparison of Outstanding Labor Disputes in the U.S. in Three Periods," prepared by the Office of the Executive Secretary, NLRB, April 1968, 17 pages; statement by AFL President William Green before Special Subcommittee of the House Labor Committee, July 1, 1946, opposing anti-strike legislation, outlining causes of postwar strikes, 9 pages; form letters; reprints of articles; notes
  - Strikes - (4) Notes, 1870-1946 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Strikes - Cases, 1960-1969 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Various legal briefs, affidavits, opinions, etc.
  - Strikes - Garment Workers, 1910 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    Six page letter from Samuel Gompers to the President of the International Ladies' Garment Workers Union re strike by cloak and suit workers, August 3, 1910
  - Strikes - Government Employees, 1911-1981 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    "Three Strikes," unsigned typescript re the Bethpage, Long Island teachers' strike, the PATCO strike and the Gary, Indiana firefighters' strike, [c. 1981], 9 pages; "The Problem," re strikes by public employees, by the Twentieth Century Fund with Philip Taft, n.d., 21 pages; "Public Collective Bargaining and Social Change," address by Chairman, New York City Office of Collective Bargaining before the American Bar Association, August 6, 1968, 6 pages; notes and photocopies of articles. See also: Government Employees, Box 7, File Folders 5-7. See also: Government Employees - New York City, Box 7, File Folder 8. See also: Teachers - Bethpage Strike, Box 11, File Folder 20. See also: Teachers - UFT, Box 12
  - Strikes - Railroad, 1885-1929 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    Notes and photocopies of articles; form letters
  - Strikes - Shopmen's, 1922 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Strikes - Textile, 1925-1941 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Strikes - Violence, 1877-1966 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    "Violence in Labor Disputes, 1877-1946," 7 page table showing name of dispute, year, numbers killed and injured, major issues; "Number of deaths by violence in work stoppages, 1937-1964," by U.S. Department of Labor, 1 page; 61 page manuscript, "Violence in Labor Disputes," beginning with p. 22, Table III; 12 page manuscript, "National Guard," list of citations in journals; four page draft, untitled, unsigned, n.d.; notes; reprint of journal article
  - Strikes - Violence - Clippings, 1937-1963 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    Many photocopies of newspaper clippings
  - Subsidies, Ship, 1899-1922 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    "Ship Subsidy" by Samuel Gompers, stating opposition, copied from the January 1907 Federationist, 5 pages; "Conference Held Tuesday, April 6, 1922 in the Executive Council Chamber, AFL ... to Consider the Ship Subsidy Bill," minutes, 5 pages; notes; clipping from May 20, 1922 International Labor News Service, AFL
  - Sweatshops (Box 11, Folder 12)
    Unsigned typescript, "Sweatshops," n.d., 2 pages
  - Table Knife Grinders, 1885 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Taft-Hartley Act, 1946-1954 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    Telegram to AFL affiliates from AFL President Green, urging them to wire Senators protesting anti-Labor legislation, May 28, 1946; statement by AFL Executive Council against anti-labor legislation pending in the Senate, May 15, 1946; "AFL National Union Heads Pledge Vigorous Fight to Repeal Labor Act and Vote Out Its Supporters," text of policy statement adopted at special conference of national and international officers, 1947 (hand notation), 4 pages (incomplete); AFL Executive Council press statement (taken from minutes) calling for repeal of Taft-Hartley, n.d. (c. 1947); letter to AFL President Green from CIO President Murray, requesting meeting to formulate a joint program, July 2, 1947; confidential report by AFL counsel J. Albert Woll, "Section 313 of the Federal Corrupt Practices Act and Its Effect on Contributions and Expenditures by Labor Organizations in Political Campaigns," December 3, 1947, 26 pages; press release by AFL President Green, commenting on report of Joint Congressional Committee on Labor-Management Relations, March 15, 1948; "Statement by Richard J. Gray, President Building and Construction Trades Department, AFL, Before the Joint Committee on Labor Management Relations of the Congress of the U.S., May 25, 1948," condemning Taft-Hartley, 12 pages; letter from AFL President Green to Acting President, International Molders and Foundry Workers, urging him to prepare a radio program against Taft-Hartley, September 30, 1948; report of the first meeting of the AFL National Legislative Council's Administrative Committee re efforts of repeal Taft-Hartley, January 11, 1949; "Statement by William Green, President, AFL before the Senate Committee on Labor and Public Welfare ... February 15, 1949, re repeal of the Taft-Hartley Act ..." 5 pages; statement of AFL President Green before the Committee on Education and Labor, U.S. House of Representatives, March 16, 1949, 5 pages plus proposed amendments; "The Taft-Hartley Act," unsigned, probably by AFL representative or legislative committee, re legislative efforts to repeal Taft-Hartley, [1949], 5 pages; "Minutes, Joint Meeting of Labor's League for Political Education and the National Legislative Council of the AFL," July 19-20, 1949; "Memo for files" by AFL legislative representatives W. C. Hushing and George Riley re "Talk With Senator Taft on reported proposed Amendments to the Taft-Hartley Act," December 15, 1950; form letter from AFL President Green with attached Building and Construction Trades Bulletin, November 29, 1951; "Statement of George D. Riley" before the Senate Subcommittee on Labor and Public Welfare, May 21, 1952, 4 pages; minutes of AFL Executive Council meeting with statement by President George Meany re President's recommendation to Congress for amendment of Taft-Hartley, January 13, 1954, 6 pages; reprint from Journal of Political Economy, Volume LVI, Number 3, June 1948: "The Closed Shop and the Taft Act."
  - Taft-Hartley Act - Notes, etc., 1947-1949 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    Includes printed checklist of Congressional voting record on Taft- Hartley and other key issues, published by AFL Labor's League for Political Education
  - Tailor's National Union (Journeymen), 1881-1883 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Tariff Commission, 1916 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Taxation, 1921-1953 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    "From the Proceedings of the AFL Convention ..." 1921-25, '29, '31: statements against sales tax; "Memo for Mr. Green," unsigned re AFL position against reduction in income tax, imposition of sales tax, July 13, 1925; "Statement by [AFL representative] W. C. Roberts before the Finance Committee of the U.S. Senate on the Estate Tax," in support, with pencil notation "1927?", 9 pages; "The Sales Tax, Otherwise the Nuisance Tax," unsigned, September 18, 1931, 4 pages; untitled, unsigned, undated manuscript with pencil notation "sales tax", apparently by AFL representative or committee, c. 1931, 6 pages; list of platform proposals submitted to Republican and Democratic Conventions by AFL, 1924 and 1928, with platforms adopted by Democrats re sales and income taxes, March 11, 1932; copy of International Labor News Service with article "Labor Says, `No Sales Tax!'" November 26, 1932; memos for Mr. Green, listing status of income tax and sales tax legislation by state, January 29, 1934; excerpts from AFL Executive Council minutes: "Legislation-Taxes, Undivided Profits," January 24-February 8, 1938, 5 pages; letter from AFL President Green to House Ways and Means Committee Chairman, supporting expansion of Social Security coverage and taxes to help finance the war, January 23, 1942; "The Revenue Act of 1942 - Recommendations of the AFL to the Finance Committee of the U.S. Senate," August 11, 1942, 12 pages; letter to AFL Vice-President Matthew Woll from AFL representative W. C. Hushing, re new tax legislation, October 30, 1942; form letters explaining Victory Tax and exemptions, February 15, 1943; letter from AFL President Green to Senate Ways and Means Committee Chairman favoring a withholding system for income tax payments, March 11, 1943, and urging consideration of AFL's social security tax proposals, November 1, 1943; resolution adopted by Executive Council calling for reduction in Cabaret Tax, May 8, 1944; press statement by AFL Committee on Taxation calling for reduction in taxes for low-income groups, November 14, 1946; statement by President Green before the Senate Finance Committee re tax reduction bills, May 2, 1947, 5 pages; "Statement of Arthur A. Elder representing the AFL before the House Ways and Means Committee on General Tax Revision," July 10, 1947, 5 pages; "Revenue Revision 1948 to remove tax injustices to permit full employment and production: Minority Report of the Special Tax Study Committee to the House Ways and Means Committee, submitted by AFL Vice-President Matthew Eoll, November 3, 1947, 32 pages and press releases re report, November 5, 1947, 5 pages, and re favorable majority reaction to report, November 6, 1947; Statement by AFL representative Lewis G. Hines before Senate Finance Committee, in support of proposed elimination of margarine tax, May 18, 1948, 3 pages; "Statement of AFL Before House Ways and Means Committee on Proposed Amendments to Federal Tax Laws," February 28, 1950; "Statement on Proposed Amendments to Revenue Act of 1950 ... In Light of Proposed Increase in Federal Expenditures by AFL," July 31, 1950, 5 pages, plus supplementary statement to Senate Finance Committee, 3 pages; minutes of AFL Executive Council re taxes, January 25, 1951; correspondence re tax bill requiring labor organizations to report income and disbursements annually, 1943-1953; form letters; notes
  - Teachers, 1938-1972 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    Letter from AFL President Green to President, New York College Teachers' Union, responding to peace overture: burden of peacemaking rests with teachers' union and depends on its rejection of CIO, October 17, 1938; letter to AFL Vice-President David Dubinsky from New York City Superintendent of Schools re Board of Education's position on six issues, January 6, 1961; "Work Stoppages Involving Teachers, 1940-62," summary release by U.S. Department of Labor, Bureau of Labor Statistics, November 1963, 8 pages; "Forth Annual Gallup Poll of Public Attitudes Toward Education," by George H. Gallup, reprint from Phi Delta Kappa, September 1972, 4 pages
  - Teachers - Bethpage Strike, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    Board brief and decision "In the Matter of Bethpage Federation of Teachers," April 11, 1969.
  - Teachers - Early Years, 1912-1920 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    Photocopied clippings from various professional and legal journals re unionization, equal pay for women, childbirth as ground for dismissal ("neglect of duty"), general issues
  - Teachers - Salary, 1925-1962 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    "Public Schools of the City of New York - History of Teachers' Salaries under control of the Board of Estimate and Apportionment," reprinted by the Joint Committee of Teachers Organizations, April 1938, from a report prepared by a committee in 1917, 9 pages; "Statement of the Rank and File: Why Reorganize the Joint Salary Committee," c. 1933; many newspaper clippings, mostly from the Bulletin of the New York Teachers Guild, 1926-62
  - Teachers - Teachers Union, 1925-1935 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    "Report on Continuation Schools" by the Sub-Committee on Continuation Schools, Committee on Experimental Education of the Teachers Union, May 3, 1929, 3 pages; press release, "Teachers Union States Its Position on the `Loyalty' Questionnaire," by TU President Henry Linville, December 21, 1934; photocopies of articles from professional journals, especially the Union Teacher, publication of the Teachers Union
  - Teachers - Teachers Union - Communist Faction, Power Struggles with, 1932-1938 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    Notice of special meeting, with attached report of the Joint Committee re charges against activities of left-wing members, October 20, 1932, 7 pages; "Report of the Special Grievance Committee" re specific charges against named left-wing members, April 18, 1933, 13 pages; "Notes on the Trial Meeting, April 29, 1933," 4 pages; "The Report of the Special Grievance Committee of the Teachers Union," April 29, 1933, 8 pages; "Resolutions and Amendments Approved by the Executive Board of the Teachers Union ..." April 29, 1933, 4 pages; "Reply to the Grievance Committee Report," by the Joint Defense Committee, n.d., c. 1933, 5 pages; "Statement by [Dr.] Abe Lefkowitz," against leftist factions in TU, n.d., with hand notation "1934?", 6 pages; "In Defense of Militant Trade Unionism: the Rank and File Reply to Dr. Linville's Statement `What Price Factionalism,'" February 27, 1935; "A Letter on the Union Investigation," by TU officers, June 7, 1935; "The Case of Local Five," criticizing TU leaders Linville and Lefkowitz, AFL investigation, signed "Teachers Union - New York City. Local Five: American Federation of Teachers," c. 1936, 3 pages; "Statement of Local 5 of the AFT to the AFL Committee," criticizing AFL investigation, etc., as above, c. 1936, 4 pages; Bulletin, Joint Committee of Teachers Organizations re expulsion of Teachers Union, with "Answer to the Joint Committee Bulletin" by Teachers Union, April 25, 1938; notes.
  - Teachers Guild - Early Years, 1935-1940 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    Flyer, "The Aims and Objectives of the New York Teachers Guild, adopted at the organization meeting," October 1, 1935; "Summary and Additional Comment," 6 page unsigned manuscript with 2 page additional fragment, n.d., re events leading to founding of Teachers Guild, apparently for organizers; press release and form letter opposing McNaboe anti-subversion investigation of New York State schools, September 16, 1936; letter to members of Guild Executive Board from Guild Executive Director Linville, calling special meeting "to perform certain necessary acts which for us will involve no factional disturbance," September 8, 1936; "Proposals For Changes In Regulations Governing Sabbatical Leave," unsigned, February 3, 1937, 3 pages; cover letter to "questionnaire on morale," not attached with other items, to Executive Board, March 1, 1937; promotional piece by Teachers Guild, May 1, 1937, 2 pages; "News Letter From New York - Sent Personally to a Limited Number," 7 page communique from Guild Executive Director Henry Linville re factional/Communist power struggles within Teachers Union, June 12, 1937; press releases (12), some re Teachers Union (responses to attacks), some re pending legislation, some in form of letters to public officials (Governor, Mayor, President of Board of Education), all 1937; "Legislative Report For 1937-1938," November 1938, 2 pages; minutes of Guild Executive Board and Delegate Assembly, 1935-39; various photocopies of Teachers Guild Bulletin and the Guild Teacher, 1937-39.
  - Teachers Guild - General, 1942-1960 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    Press releases: (re juvenile delinquency, October 4, 1943, 4 pages; re Committee on Human Relations, supporting protest resignation of chairmen, criticizing mayor, Board of Education and Superintendent of Schools, October 17 and 29, 1945; opposing Teachers Council, November 2, 1945; re uncovered classes at one school, October 31, 1945; decrying "lack of discussion between teachers and school officials" (copies of letters to mayor and President, Board of Education), June 1954; opposing requirement for teachers to reveal names of subversives, February 21, 1955; decrying teacher shortage, January 7, 1958; favoring unity plan to create United Federation of Teachers, March 16, 1960); memorandum to Guild Executive Board from Guild Special representative re merger policy, January 25, 1960, 2 pages; "McNaboe Resolution for Inquiry" creating join committee of state legislature to investigate subversive activities in schools, n.d., 2 pages; "Resolution adopted Unanimously by the Executive Board of the New York Teachers Guild (AFL) on Wednesday, April 20, 1955 - [In the Matter] of Charges Preferred by the Board of Higher Education Against V. McGill, Louis Weisner and Charles W. Hughes," deploring requirement to disclose names of Communist Party members by ex-affiliates; notice of meeting to prepare for meeting with school Superintendent and other officials re "Democratization of the School Administration," January 11, 1946; "Towards Democratization of School Administration," resume of statements by Guild representatives at meeting held at Board of Education, February 6, 1946, 6 pages; "Restore Teacher Morale and End the Boycott," statement by Guild legislative representative before the Meyer fact-finding committee of the New York City Board of Education, December 5, 1950, 7 pages; "Needed Salary Adjustments in the NYC Schools," statement by Guild President before the Meyer fact-finding committee of the New York City Board of Education, December 5, 1950, 5 pages; "Statement Before the NYC Board of Education, Thursday, March 1, 1951 on the Meyer Committee Report"; several press releases re "Minimum Service Program" (i.e., work slowdown) by Guild, May-June 1954; guidelines for "Minimum Service Program" re extracurricular activities, class trips and other non-mandated services, c. 1954, 2 sheets; statement by Guild Educational Policy Committee re "difficult schools", 4 pages, with pencil notation "1956 or 1957"; "Report of a Special Committee of the New York Teachers Guild" opposing forced transfers, January 30, 1957, 2 pages; "Guild Action in the Case of Alma Fabricus," June 30, 1942-January 4, 1943, 2 pages; correspondence.
  - Teachers Guild - General, 1940-1960 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    "School Crisis Fact Book," 9 pages, 1947; the "Mid-Summer Letter" to Guild Executive Board, July 20, 1954, 2 pages; photocopies of articles from the Guild Teacher: "The 1941 AF of T Convention", "Developments in School Laws, 1940-41", "Local 2 Launches Challenging Legislative Campaign for 1941"; "The 1958 Legislative Program," 2 pages plus one page 26-point "complete" program of Guild; "Amendments to the By-Laws of the Board of Education Recommended by the Teachers' Guild of NYC In Order to Improve Procedural Practices," n.d., 2 pages; "How the Clancy Law Works," aids in computing pension reserves and rates, by Guild, n.d., c. 1951; Guild Executive Board minutes, 1960 (plus one 1949 and 1959); Guild Delegate Assembly minutes, 1940-41; D. A. Reporter, February 14, 1951, number 34 and number 21, n.d.; form letter; routine letter, 1945 and 1946
  - Teachers Guild - General - Clippings, 1941-1960 (Box 11, Folder 28)
    Photocopies of Guild publications, mostly the Guild Teacher and the Guild Bulletin
  - Teachers Guild - Bureau of Child Guidance, 1945-1962 (Box 11, Folder 29)
    Letter from Guild President to New York City Board of Education President re staff shortages in the Bureau of Child Guidance, non-competitive, newly reduced, starting salary, comparing with salary and requirements of building attendants, December 14, 1945; "Bureau of Child Guidance," statement of Guild representative at Budget Hearing, New York City Board of Education, November 30, 1945, criticizing unrealistic starting salary and requirements as cause of shortage of school social workers, 3 pages; letter from Guild President to New York City Board of Education President, re salary schedule of substitute school social workers and psychologists, November 7, 1951; form letter to Bureau of Child Guidance (BCG) members supporting the Staff Relations Plan, March 28, 1952; "Brief in Support of Teacher Status for School Social Worker and Psychologists as Provided by the Cuite and Bubin Bills Before the 1956 State Legislature," 13 page report by New York City Teachers Guild, January 26, 1956; "Teachers Status For Psychologists and Social Workers in the Bureau of Child Guidance," Prepared by Guild representative, January 17, 1956, 2 pages; letter from Guild President to New York City Board of Education President protesting salary schedules for social workers and psychologists, May 31, 1956; letter from President, Guild Bureau of Child Guidance Chapter to Chairman of Board of Examiners, New York City Board of Education, protesting delay in announcing appointment lists for school social workers, psychologists and supervisors, September 18, 1956; "Brief Opposing the Proposed Qualifying Examination for the Position of Assistant Administrative Director in the Bureau of Child Guidance and Asking for Such a Delineation of the Functions of this New Position So That There is No Danger Of Intrusion On the Professional Prestige and Integrity of the Clinical Leadership," c. 1956, 2 pages; "Brief in Support of Increased Budgetary Provisions for the Bureau of Child Guidance," presented to the Board of Education at the Budget Hearing on January 27, 1958, by the Bureau of Child Guidance Chapter of the New York Teachers Guild, 4 pages; press releases, copies of the Bureau Guild Reporter, (one later issue, 1963, called Child Guidance Chapter, UFT Reporter)
  - Teachers Guild - Class Size, 1941-1965 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    Guild press releases (1941-60), correspondence with Superintendent of Schools, Mayor (1954-59) re false class registers, misleading publication of "average" class size figures, and need for conferences; "Why Have You Asked That the Members Board of Education be Removed From Office?" statement recorded for John Wingate Program, WOR radio (New York City), n.d., c. 1952; unsigned 3 page manuscript, apparently by Guild, re evasion of class size limitations as mandated by "Regulations of the Commissioner of Education of the State of New York," and administrative appeal by Guild to compel conformity, c. 1952; brief of appeal by United Federation of Teachers (UFT), "In the Matter of the Appeal of Franklin Smith," 1960, incorporating by reference Guild appeal "In the Matter of Simon," 1956; One UFT press release, October 24, 1961, clippings
  - Teachers Guild - Educational Policies Committee, 1956-1957 (Box 11, Folder 31)